<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Kaitlyn Fichtner</title>
    <link>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Kaitlyn Fichtner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 11:14:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recycling Sorting Machine Learning Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/recycling-sorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/recycling-sorting/</guid>
      <description>Recycling and composting rates have been steadily increasing from 6.0% of total Municipal Solid Waste (MSW) in 1960 to 32.1% of MSW in 2018 [1]. With a growing amount of waste being recycled, automating the process of sorting recycling would make recycling facilities more efficient and improve conditions for workers. Recycling workers are at risk for severe injuries including loss of limb if caught between moving machinery, being crushed by equipment, injuries from falls, and hand or finger amputation or laceration from sharp objects [2,3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Detection Research Internship</title>
      <link>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/fire-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/fire-detection/</guid>
      <description>Entrapment is a deadly safety concern for wildland firefighters. It occurs when firebrands ignite spotfires that quickly spread, blocking the firefighters escape routes and safety zones. The objective of this research is to develop a camera-based method for detecting spotfires that will be used in a low-cost, lightweight device worn by firefighters.
Summary:   Developed a color ratio method for detecting fire to be used in a portable, low-cost device for enhancing wildland firefighter safety.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
