<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Vision on Kaitlyn Fichtner</title>
    <link>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/tags/computer-vision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Vision on Kaitlyn Fichtner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/tags/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fire Detection Research Internship</title>
      <link>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/fire-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/fire-detection/</guid>
      <description>Entrapment is a deadly safety concern for wildland firefighters. It occurs when firebrands ignite spotfires that quickly spread, blocking the firefighters escape routes and safety zones. The objective of this research is to develop a camera-based method for detecting spotfires that will be used in a low-cost, lightweight device worn by firefighters.
Summary:   Developed a color ratio method for detecting fire to be used in a portable, low-cost device for enhancing wildland firefighter safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Sorting Robotic Arm</title>
      <link>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/sorting-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kofichtner.github.io/Kaitlyn_Fichtner_Portfolio/post/sorting-robot/</guid>
      <description>Using a 3-dof robotic arm with a camera positioned above its task space, my team of 3 used computer vision to detect, locate, and sort objects by color and size.
Summary:   Applied transformation matrices to convert pixel coordinates to positions in the task space. Implemented image segmentation techniques and color masking to locate and sort objects by color and size. Utilized inverse differential kinematic controls for smoother movements. Continuously searched the task space so that the arm could dynamically follow moving objects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
